Finding Aid for L. Brooks Patterson papers, 1975-2007
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
L. Brooks Patterson papers 1975-2007
Patterson, L. Brooks.
07184 Aa 2
County Executive of Oakland County Michigan since 1992, former prosecuting attorney in Oakland County; collection includes typed copies of Patterson's speeches, roasts, and editorials; newspaper clippings on topics important to Patterson; press releases; and promotional and other videotapes.
5 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records were donated by L. Brooks Patterson (donor no. 9941 ) in 2007.
Periodic additions to the records expected.
The collection is open to research.
Patterson received a bachelor's degree from the University of Detroit, and his Juris Doctorate in 1967 from its law school. Upon graduation, he was hired by the Oakland County Prosecuting Attorney as an assistant prosecutor. He left that post in 1971, and in 1972 he ran for Oakland County Prosecutor, winning and serving in this capacity until 1988, when he left for a private law practice. He ran unsuccessfully for the Senate in 1978. In 1992, Patterson was elected Oakland County Executive. He was three-times re-elected. While in this position, Patterson has been involved in many issues, particularly Oakland County-Detroit relations, economic development in Oakland County, and the founding of Automation Alley.
In his career, Patterson has received many honors, including the State of Israel Eleanor Roosevelt Humanities Award in 1996, the March of Dimes Humanitarian of the Year Award; Oakland County Distinguished Citizen of 1991; and the Outstanding Young Men of Michigan Award in 1973. In 1980, Patterson founded the Rainbow Connection, a charity that grants wishes to children with life threatening illnesses.
The L. Brooks Patterson collection includes typed copies of Patterson's speeches, roasts, and editorials; newspaper clippings on topics important to Patterson; press releases; and promotional and other videotapes. The collection is organized into the following series: Speeches, Roasts, Press, Miscellaneous, and Other Media.
Subjects:
Patterson, L. Brooks.; Oakland County (Mich.). Executive.; Oakland County (Mich.)--Politics and government.; Republican Party (Mich.)
Genre Terms:
Videotapes.
- Speeches
  The Speeches series, the bulk of the collection, includes speeches from 1975 to 2007. The topics of the speeches range from economic forecasts, state of the county addresses, charity events, economic development, patriotic events, and so on. They reflect the wide variety of issues Patterson has faced while in office.
  - 1974-1980
    - Youth speeches 1974 (Box 1)
    - Lincoln Day Dinner 1975 (Box 1)
    - Should marijuana be Decriminalized 1975 (Box 1)
    - Impact of Crime on Michigan March 1976 (Box 1)
    - Alma Kiwanis Club Annual Gratiot County Law Enforcement "Recognition Banquet April 28, 1976 (Box 1)
    - Welfare 1976 (Box 1)
    - James D. Wines Dinner September 14, 1976 (Box 1)
    - Pontiac Mall Home Builders Show May 22, 1977 (Box 1)
    - Observation on the Republican Senatorial Primary 1978 (Box 1)
    - Michigan Women's and Children Apparel, Shoplifting January 16, 1978 (Box 1)
    - Testimony Before the Judiciary Committee on Spouse Abuse Legislation February 6, 1978 (Box 1)
    - Clarkston Area Boy Scout's Awards Dinner February 15, 1978 (Box 1)
    - Fraternal Order of Police State Lodge Banquet Dinner June 25, 1978 (Box 1)
    - Lt. Governor Brickley Dinner August 21, 1979 (Box 1)
    - Reagan Speech 1980 (Box 1)
    - Michigan Association Chiefs of Police February 6, 1980 (Box 1)
  - 1981-1984
    - Michigan Governor's Conference on Agriculture--Horse Industry Committee Report April 1-2, 1981 (Box 1)
    - Cable Fights Crime Seminar June 13, 1981 (Box 1)
    - Craft-Baressi Consultants Office Building Dedication July 26, 1981 (Box 1)
    - Leonard Gilman Luncheon July 31, 1981 (Box 1)
    - Michigan Department of Agriculture August 31, 1981 (Box 1)
    - HBPA September 13, 1982 (Box 1)
    - Republican State Convention Detroit February 19, 1983 (Box 1)
    - Oakland County Police Academy Graduation April 15, 1983 (Box 1)
    - St. Mary's Prep Commencement May 22, 1983 (Box 1)
    - 15th Biennial Mackinac Island Republican Leadership Conference September 24, 1983 (Box 1)
    - Reagan Speeches 1984 (Box 1)
    - Republican State Convention, Grand Rapids January 28-30, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Joseph Knollenberg Nomination for Chairman for Republican Committee of Oakland County February 23, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Senate Republic Majority Dinner May 11, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Theme of the Appearance for the DEA Seminar June 1984 (Box 1)
    - Republican State Convention Cobo Hall September 8, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Second Annual Lake Michigan Conference September 13, 1984 (Box 1)
  - 1985-1990
    - Lincoln Day Dinner February 7, 1985 (Box 1)
    - Leonard Gilman, Night of the Ballpark February 13-August 1985 (Box 1)
    - Remarks before the Republican State Convention, Grand Rapids February 16, 1985 (Box 1)
    - Remarks Before the State Republican Committee Meeting April 18, 1985 (Box 1)
    - Lincoln Day Dinner Benzie County May 31, 1985 (Box 1)
    - Michigan Association of Insurance Companies June 10, 1985 (Box 1)
    - Livonia Chamber of Commerce Spring Luncheon June 12, 1985 (Box 1)
    - Midwest Leadership Conference June 21-22, 1985 (Box 1)
    - Michigan Association of Realtors Breakfast Speech July 4, 1985 (Box 1)
    - Mackinac Republican Leadership Conference September 22, 1985 (Box 1)
    - Distinguished Citizen Dinner December 5, 1985 (Box 1)
    - Lincoln Day Dinner Oakland County January 1, 1986 (Box 1)
    - Boy Scout #179 Eagle Scout Court of Honor January 7, 1986 (Box 1)
    - Governor Introduction January 22, 1987 (Box 1)
    - First Annual Statewide Lincoln Day Dinner February 21, 1986 (Box 1)
    - Men of Mercy May 5, 1986 (Box 1)
    - Introduction of Dick Chrysler May 16, 1986 (Box 1)
    - Police Athletic League, September 16,1986 (Box 1)
    - Mapers Spring Conference May 18, 1987 (Box 1)
    - EMS Providers Training Institute Graduation June 23, 1987 (Box 1)
    - Dorsey Business School Veterans Memorial June 25, 1987 (Box 1)
    - Republican Presidential Candidates January 7, 1988 (Box 1)
    - Oakland County Lincoln Day Dinner February 13, 1988 (Box 1)
    - Michael Dukakis (campaign speech on) October 4, 1988 (Box 1)
    - Jardon School Senior Honors Night June 5, 1989 (Box 1)
    - 4th Annual Guest House Golf Classic June 12, 1989 (Box 1)
    - Catch Dinner September 7, 1989 (Box 1)
    - Sarah Fisher Home Golf Outing September 12, 1989 (Box 1)
    - Oakland County Bar People's Law School Presentation March 27, 1990 (Box 1)
    - Lynn Allen Open Golf Outing June 8, 1990 (Box 1)
    - 3rd Annual Golf Outing Clarkston Chamber of Commerce August 7, 1990 (Box 1)
    - The Osgood File September 25, 1990 (Box 1)
    - Crain's Business Detroit Press Club October 3, 1990 (Box 1)
    - CATCH Dinner, October 4,1990 (Box 1)
    - March of Dimes December 4, 1990 (Box 1)
    - B.O.M.A. Luncheon December 14, 1990 (Box 1)
  - 1991-1994
    - Engler's Inaugural Ball January 4, 1991 (Box 1)
    - Boy's and Girl's Club February 22, 1991 (Box 1)
    - Councilman Gil Hill Letter, March 9 1991 (Box 1)
    - 4th Annual Golf Outing Clarkston Chamber of Commerce August 6, 1991 (Box 1)
    - Sheriff's Boot Camp Grad August 30, 1991 (Box 1)
    - 19th Bicentennial Republican Leadership Conference September 21, 1991 (Box 1)
    - Career Day Brother Rice October 17, 1991 (Box 1)
    - Boys and Girls Club February 17, 1992 (Box 1)
    - Troy Youth Assistance April 8, 1992 (Box 1)
    - St. Clair County Event April 11, 1992 (Box 1)
    - Men of Mercy May 5, 1992 (Box 1)
    - YMCA Volunteerism May 27, 1992 (Box 1)
    - POH Booster Benefit Club Golf Outing June 8, 1992 (Box 1)
    - Police Academy Graduation Washtenaw County July 31, 1992 (Box 1)
    - County Republican Convention November 18, 1992 (Box 1)
    - Mackinac Leadership Conference September 19, 1993 (Box 1)
    - Washington D.C. October Fest October 27, 1993 (Box 1)
    - Economic Club of Detroit, January 7 1994 (Box 1)
    - Boys and Girls Club of Auburn Hills February 28, 1994 (Box 1)
    - Judson Center Annual Meeting, May 3 1994 (Box 1)
    - Metro North Michigan State Police Post May 18, 1994 (Box 1)
    - Pontiac Area Urban League Annual Dinner May 25, 1994 (Box 1)
    - Veteran's Memorial Dedication May 28, 1994 (Box 1)
    - Big 4 Partners for Progress Mackinac Island June 3, 1994 (Box 1)
    - Oakland County Family and Neighborhood Empowerment Breakfast July 20, 1994 (Box 1)
    - BMX Opening Ceremonies July 29, 1994 (Box 1)
    - Matt West Golf Outing August 13, 1994 (Box 1)
    - Matt West Golf Outing September 25, 1994 (Box 1)
    - Haggerty Road Connector Opening October 27, 1994 (Box 1)
    - Judge Benjamin Friedman Recognition Dinner November 29, 1994 (Box 1)
    - American Axle & Manufacturing Inc. High Tech Center Groundbreaking Ceremony December 16, 1994 (Box 1)
  - 1995-1996
    - Distinguished Citizen Award January 12, 1995 (Box 1)
    - Beavers January 19, 1995 (Box 1)
    - Henry Saad Investiture January 26, 1995 (Box 1)
    - Announcement of New Plastics Plant Coming to Pontiac January 27, 1995 (Box 1)
    - Troy High School Orchestra Gala January 28, 1995 (Box 1)
    - Economic Club January 31, 1995 (Box 1)
    - State of the County Address February 22, 1995 (Box 1)
    - March of Dimes Sweetheart Ball March 4, 1995 (Box 1)
    - Andi Fischer Farewell Dinner March 28, 1995 (Box 1)
    - 52nd District Court 1st Division Dedication May 1, 1995 (Box 1)
    - Detroit Golf Club President's Night May 12, 1995 (Box 1)
    - Dedication of the Hayden Building May 12, 1995 (Box 1)
    - 21st Century Golf Outing May 17, 1995 (Box 1)
    - World Trade Week May 24, 1995 (Box 1)
    - Grand Opening "One-Stop-Shop" Customer Service Center August 30, 1995 (Box 1)
    - Grand Opening Export Assistance Center September 8, 1995 (Box 1)
    - Republican Leadership Conference September 22-24, 1995 (Box 1)
    - Healthy People/Healthy Oakland November 30, 1995 (Box 1)
    - State of the County Address February 6, 1996 (Box 1)
    - Lincoln Day Dinner, February / March 1996 (Box 1)
    - Henry William Saad Fundraiser March 7, 1996 (Box 1)
    - Introduction of George Will Friends of Mercy Celebrity Night May 14, 1996 (Box 1)
    - Men of Mercy Introductions May 14, 1996 (Box 1)
    - Eleanor Roosevelt Humanitarian Award State of Israel Bonds June 4, 1996 (Box 1)
    - Dedication of North Lobby Entrance June 10, 1996 (Box 1)
    - Presentation to State Lawmakers July 17, 1996 (Box 1)
    - Oakland School to Work Partnerships Executive Meeting June 18, 1996 (Box 1)
    - Speech to Oakland Schools Staff August 26, 1996 (Box 1)
    - Proposal "E" News Conference October 30, 1996 (Box 1)
    - Young Presidents Organization November 13, 1996 (Box 1)
    - HRFIS Project Kickoff Presentation November 25, 1996 (Box 1)
    - Economic Club of Detroit Luncheon December 16, 1996 (Box 1)
  - 1997-1999
    - Hilda Gage Investiture January 22, 1997 (Box 1)
    - Public School Pride Day February 2, 1997 (Box 1)
    - Lincoln Day Dinner March 1, 1997 (Box 1)
    - State of the County Address March 6, 1997 (Box 1)
    - Risk and Insurance Management Society March 18, 1997 (Box 1)
    - Economic Forecast News Conference and Luncheon April 18, 1997 (Box 2)
    - Youth Appreciation Breakfast May 13, 1997 (Box 2)
    - New Directions Institute Open House May 20, 1997 (Box 2)
    - Remarks for Children's Summit of Oakland County June 2, 1997 (Box 2)
    - Vince Brennan Golf Outing June 2, 1997 (Box 2)
    - South Lyon Police Department August 26, 1997 (Box 2)
    - Gold Key Event Program September 12, 1997 (Box 2)
    - Oakland County Republicans 50th Anniversary Celebration January 22, 1998 (Box 2)
    - Senate Judiciary Sub-Committee on Immigration Testimony October 14, 1997 (Box 2)
    - Road Commission for Oakland County Safety Banquet October 16, 1997 (Box 2)
    - District Judges Association October 21, 1997 (Box 2)
    - 25th Anniversary Lighthouse November 18, 1997 (Box 2)
    - State of the County Address February 26, 1998 (Box 2)
    - Lincoln Day Dinner February 27, 1998 (Box 2)
    - Harold Bulgarelli Retirement Dinner May 18, 1998 (Box 2)
    - Eulogy for Sheriff John Nichols December 23, 1998 (Box 2)
    - Legislative Informational Seminar January 15, 1999 (Box 2)
    - State of the County Address February 18, 1999 (Box 2)
    - Economic Forecast Luncheon April 22, 1999 (Box 2)
    - Economic Club of Detroit Introducing Remarks for Elizabeth Dole April 29, 1999 (Box 2)
    - LBP's Local Option Gas Tax Proposal June 29, 1999 (Box 2)
    - Gambling July 29, 1999 (Box 2)
    - Plymouth Wayne Inc./Advanced Robotic Concepts Dedication Ceremonies August 25, 1999 (Box 2)
    - Lawrence Technological University Groundbreaking August 18, 1999 (Box 2)
    - Hayden Inc. September 7, 1999 (Box 2)
    - Automation Alley News Conference, Meritor Automotive September 13, 1999 (Box 2)
    - Sika Corporation September 29, 1999 (Box 2)
    - Chrysler Museum Dedication September 30, 1999 (Box 2)
    - Huron River Fishing Club October 12, 1999 (Box 2)
    - Tribute to Justice October 14, 1999 (Box 2)
    - E-Commerce Business Forum October 14, 1999 (Box 2)
    - South Oakland Office Building Dedication November 5, 1999 (Box 2)
    - Lynn Allen Eulogy November 6, 1999 (Box 2)
    - Oakland County Business Roundtable Annual Meeting December 9, 1999 (Box 2)
    - SMART Big 3 Media Event December 1, 1999 (Box 2)
  - 2000
    - Polish-American Club Introduction of George Bush February 4, 2000 (Box 2)
    - IBJ Economic Network Luncheon February 9, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Toast of the Town February 10, 2000 (Box 2)
    - SMART Speech Michigan Public Transit Association February 15, 2000 (Box 2)
    - State of the County Address February 17, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Nancy Carniak Investiture February 22, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Little Oaks Dedication March 14, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Economic Club Introduction of Dr. Keiji Tachikawa March 27, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Michigan Works! Service Center Certification Ceremony March 28, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Hometown Heroes Luncheon March 29, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Smart Growth Conference April 14, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Woodward Avenue Action Association Check Presentation April 18, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Announcement Breakfast May 9, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Deneb Robotics June 7, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Collins and Aikman, Global Headquarters Division June 29, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Waterford Foundation Golf Outing June 19, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Jackie Stewart Eulogy June 23, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Collins-Aikman Global Headquarters Dedication June 29, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Arvin Meritor Reception July 10, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Autoliv Networking Session July 18, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Prosecutor's Golf Outing July 19, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Convisint News Conference August 17, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Seconding Speech Justices August 26, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Continental Teves Dedication September 7, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Flint Marketing Executives September 21, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Connections 2000 October 2, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Oakland Schools 2001 Project October 9, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Oxford Gala Celebration October 12, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Tesco Group Headquarters Grand Opening October 12, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Oakland County: A Premier Global Technology Center and Leisure Time Wonderland December 18, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Michigan Society of Association Executives November 2, 2000 (Box 2)
    - 'On My Own' of Michigan 3rd Annual Awards Dinner November 16, 2000 (Box 2)
  - 2001
    - Rae Lee Chabot Investiture February 15, 2001 (Box 2)
    - Lincoln Day Dinner February 10, 2001 (Box 2)
    - State of the County Address February 13, 2001 (Box 2)
    - Investiture of Honorable Elizabeth Pezzetti February 27, 2001 (Box 2)
    - State of the County Address March 1, 2001 (Box 2)
    - Area Code speech April 2001 (Box 2)
    - Celebrity Night May 8, 2001 (Box 2)
    - John Joseph Maher Wake May 22, 2001 (Box 2)
    - Information Technology Plan for Environmental Infrastructure May 20, 2001 (Box 2)
    - Quake-on-the-Lake News Conference June 12, 2001 (Box 2)
    - ITEC Keynote Address June 20, 2001 (Box 2)
    - West Nile Virus August 23, 2001 (Box 2)
    - Groundbreaking Ceremony for Quality Suites Hotel and Conference Center August 21, 2001 (Box 2)
    - ExperienceSeniorPower News Conference August 15, 2001 (Box 2)
    - University of Detroit Golf Outing August 24, 2001 (Box 2)
    - Automation Alley Black Tie Awards Gala September 7, 2001 (Box 2)
    - Brownfield Initiative News Conference September 11, 2001 (Box 2)
    - MEDC News Conference September 17, 2001 (Box 2)
    - Patriotic Rally September 17, 2001 (Box 2)
    - James Alexander Commissioners October 30, 2001 (Box 2)
    - Merry Go Round Gala Introduction of David Gorcyca November 3, 2001 (Box 2)
  - 2002
    - State of the County Address February 13, 2002 (Box 2)
    - Lincoln Day Dinner February 23, 2002 (Box 2)
    - Altair Engineering New World Headquarters Grand Opening April 17, 2002 (Box 2)
    - Economic Outlook Luncheon May 1, 2002 (Box 2)
    - G8 Session 3B May 2, 2002 (Box 2)
    - Breakfast with Brooks Intro of Ed McMahon May 23, 2002 (Box 2)
    - Auditorium Dedication June 13, 2002 (Box 2)
    - Waterford Foundation Introduction of Forrest Milzow June 17, 2002 (Box 2)
    - Michigan International Trade Association June 25, 2002 (Box 2)
    - Mackinac Center for Public Policy July 24, 2002 (Box 2)
    - Automation Alley/TARDEC News Conference August 12, 2002 (Box 2)
    - Detroit Regional Chamber Meeting August 22, 2002 (Box 2)
    - Talking Points Rouge 2002 Oakland County Clean Water, September 20, 2002 (Box 2)
    - DSU Golf Outing September 23, 2002 (Box 2)
    - Orion Township Assembly Plant October 2, 2002 (Box 2)
    - NAACP Dinner October 11, 2002 (Box 2)
    - Oracle User's Group October 24, 2002 (Box 2)
    - Credit Union Open House November 7, 2002 (Box 2)
    - Judge Jerry McNally Retirement November 13, 2002 (Box 2)
    - National Cemetery Land Transfer November 21, 2002 (Box 2)
    - Michigan Democratic Party October 4, 2002 (Box 2)
    - Oakland County Business Roundtable Annual Meeting December 5, 2002 (Box 2)
    - Introduction of Jennifer Granholm Oakland County Business Roundtable December 5, 2002 (Box 2)
  - 2003
    - Ficano Inaugural Committee Luncheon January 3, 2003 (Box 2)
    - Delphi Automotive January 10, 2003 (Box 2)
    - State of the County Address February 12, 2003 (Box 2)
    - Link Michigan Press Conference March 5, 2003 (Box 2)
    - Lincoln Day Dinner Introduction of Mary Matalin March 14, 2003 (Box 2)
    - ERP Conference March 27, 2003 (Box 2)
    - Easter Seals Luncheon March 28, 2003 (Box 2)
    - Alice Gustafson Eulogy, March 331 2003 (Box 2)
    - WLN High School Dedication April 13, 2003 (Box 2)
    - Len Gilman Covault Award April 15, 2003 (Box 2)
    - Economic Forecast Luncheon May 1, 2003 (Box 2)
    - Remarks Before the Transportation Committee of the Michigan Senate Chair, Senator Judson Gilbert May 5, 2003 (Box 2)
    - Hazmat News Conference July 16, 2003 (Box 2)
    - Online Services News Conference May 14, 2003 (Box 2)
    - Automation Alley Mexico Trade Mission July 2, 2003 (Box 2)
    - Walsh College Remarks July 21, 2003 (Box 2)
    - Automation Alley Reverse Trade Mission News Conference August 20, 2003 (Box 3)
    - Jascha Gelmen Memorial Fund Golf Outing August 25, 2003 (Box 3)
    - For Public Comment Adoption of Budget Board of Commissioner's Meeting September 18, 2003 (Box 3)
    - Community Service Garden Dedication September 10, 2003 (Box 3)
    - MIRA 11th Anniversary Gold Key September 20, 2003 (Box 3)
    - Saint Peter's Paul Jesuit Charity Event, September 24 2003 (Box 3)
    - Leadership Speech Andover High School September 30, 2003 (Box 3)
    - Joe Dumar Introduction October 6, 2003 (Box 3)
    - National Veteran's Cemetery Holly Township October 6, 2003 (Box 3)
    - Hayes Jones October 7, 2003 (Box 3)
    - Leadership Academy Grad Ceremony October 8, 2003 (Box 3)
    - Blackout of 2003 Recognition, October 16, 2003 (Box 3)
    - Oakland County Bar Review Talent Show October 22, 2003 (Box 3)
    - Future Testimony on Ruth Johnson Legislation October 29, 2003 (Box 3)
    - Future Testimony on House Bill No. 4338 October 30, 2003 (Box 3)
    - Welcome Hollister Introduction December 4, 2003 (Box 3)
    - Flu Vaccine Press Conference December 11, 2003 (Box 3)
    - 52 District Court "Pay Tickets," December 9, 2003 (Box 3)
    - Dr. Robert Aranosian Eulogy December 22, 2003 (Box 3)
  - 2004
    - State of the County Address February 12, 2004 (Box 3)
    - Older Person's Commission, New Building Dedication February 13, 2004 (Box 3)
    - First Annual CAF Fundraiser February 28, 2004 (Box 3)
    - Autism Rooted In Hope Tree Planting Ceremony April 6, 2004 (Box 3)
    - U of M Economic Forecast Luncheon April 29, 2004 (Box 3)
    - Annual Volunteer Probation Officer Dinner April 29, 2004 (Box 3)
    - DOT News Conference April 30, 2004 (Box 3)
    - Cover the Uninsured Week May 10, 2004 (Box 3)
    - Mapus Conference May 24, 2004 (Box 3)
    - JVS June 10, 2004 (Box 3)
    - Grant Thorton June 16, 2004 (Box 3)
    - Republican Executive Committee June 24, 2004 (Box 3)
    - HAZMAT Bullet Points July 28, 2004 (Box 3)
    - Cyber Tour News Conference July 20, 2004 (Box 3)
    - POH Medical Center September 27, 2004 (Box 3)
    - Q2 Breakfast October 5, 2004 (Box 3)
    - Diversity Press Conference October 13, 2004 (Box 3)
    - Veteran's Cemetery Dedication October 14, 2004 (Box 3)
    - Ground Run-Up Enclosure Dedication Oakland County International Airport October 20, 2004 (Box 3)
    - Community Summit on Homelessness November 22, 2004 (Box 3)
    - Oakvideo Launch November 23, 2004 (Box 3)
  - 2005
    - State of the County Address February 12, 2005 (Box 3)
    - Dan Murphy Eulogy February 26, 2005 (Box 3)
    - Judicial Investiture Ceremony Kelley Kostin March 2005 (Box 3)
    - Harvard University March 7, 2005 (Box 3)
    - Diversity Conference April 14, 2005 (Box 3)
    - 52-4 District Court Volunteer Probation Counselor Recognition Program April 25, 2005 (Box 3)
    - Economic Outlook Luncheon April 28, 2005 (Box 3)
    - Senior Advising Council and Parks and Recreation Legislation Breakfast May 13, 2005 (Box 3)
    - Wireless Oakland (Draft 3) June 15, 2005 (Box 3)
    - Troy PAC "Breakfast with Brooks Patterson" June 14, 2005 (Box 3)
    - Quake on the Lake July 23-24, 2005 (Box 3)
    - Michigan Urban Search and Rescue/Operating Engineer's Training August 7, 2005 (Box 3)
    - SAVE Task Force Symposium September 15, 2005 (Box 3)
    - Academy of the Sacred Field House Dedication September 16, 2005 (Box 3)
    - Purchasing Division Accreditation October 10, 2005 (Box 3)
    - Oakland County Health Division Flu Shot Clinic October 29, 2005 (Box 3)
    - Fallen Heroes Memorial Dedication November 21, 2005 (Box 3)
    - OCC Police Academy Graduation December 9, 2005 (Box 3)
    - Comments on the 2006-2007 Recommended Budget, July 13, 2005 (Box 3)
    - Recommended Budget for 2006-2007 Rebuttal Comments, July 13, 2005 (Box 3)
    - Oakland County General II 2005 (Box 3)
    - Van Buren BBQ 2005 (Box 3)
    - Introductory Remarks for Maureen Reagan 2005 (Box 3)
    - Oakland County's Role in Southeast Michigan 2005 (Box 3)
  - 2006-2007
    - State of the County Address January 11, 2006 (Box 3)
    - State of the County Address (on several topics) February 8, 2006 (Box 3)
    - Leadership Oakland March 2, 2006 (Box 3)
    - Global Trade Mission March 6, 2006 (Box 3)
    - Oakland County Economic Outlook Luncheon April 26, 2006 (Box 3)
    - Homeland Security Conference June 7, 2006 (Box 3)